Guide to the New York City COVID-19 Web Activism Collection TAM.798
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York City COVID-19 Web Activism Collection
May 2020-ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Free Them All for Public Health
Fund Excluded Workers Coalition
NoBody Is Disposable Coalition
COVID Bail Out NYC
Beyond Prisons
DRUM (Organization)
Smalls, Chris
Audre Lorde Project
Krongelb, Malana
Betancourt Macias Family Scholarship Foundation
Butterfly: Asian and Migrant Sex Workers Support Network
Maggie's Toronto Sex Workers Action Project
Corona Courier
Cosecha
Democratic Socialists of America
Dollar Bail Brigade
Freelance Solidarity Project
Herbalista
Housing Justice for All
Hunter College. New York City Food Policy Center
Justice Committee
Kwon, Tre
Make the Road (New York)
Metrowest Worker Center
Movement of Rank and File Educators
Mutual Aid NYC
National Harm Reduction Coalition
New York City COVID-19 Action
New York Immigration Coalition
NYC Covid Care Network
NYC United Against Coronavirus
NYC Veterans Alliance
Piepzna-Samarasinha, Leah Lakshmi, 1975-
Public Power Coalition
Queens Neighborhoods United
Rent Strike 2020
Right to Counsel NYC Coalition
Sex Workers Outreach Project Brooklyn
Talen, Bill
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.)
West Side Federation for Senior Housing
Workers Need Childcare
Gonzalez, Yessica
#NamingTheLost
Zip Code Memory Project
1014 (Gallery)
American Society on Aging
Artforum
Asian American/Asian Research Institute
The Associated Press
The Atlantic Monthly
Bari, Kisha
Chang, Jasmin
Bloomberg News (Firm)
Bronx Documentary Center
Brown University. Department of Africana Studies
California
California State University
Cineaste
THE CITY
Columbia University
Columbia University. Press
Dartmouth University
Detroit Riverfront Conservancy
Frieze Art Fair
Globe Newspaper Co.
Gotham Center for New York City History
Hyperallergic
Johns Hopkins University
Killebrew, Sonja J
Lozano-Hemmer, Rafael
Mark-n-Sparks, Inc.
Memorial Crane Project
Modernist Studies Association
Monument Lab (Art studio)
Museum of Chinese in the Americas
The Nation, New York.
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
National Geographic Partners (U.S.)
National Museum of the American Indian (U.S.)
The New republic
New York Times Company
New York University
New York University. Asian/Pacific/American Studies Program and Institute
New York University. Center for Disability Studies
NYU Press
The Opportunity Atlas
Queens Borough Public Library
Reading the Pictures
Rios, Desiree A.
River City Journalism Fund
Rothermere American Institute
Smithsonian Institution
Thompson, John Henry
Johnson, Shindy
Time, inc.
Keeves, Christine
Urquiza, Kristin
Vermont Public
Virginia Quarterly Review
Washington Post Company
Wired
YARA + DAVINA
TAM.798
224 websites in 224 archived websites.
The NYC COVID-19 Web Activism Collection, assembled by Tamiment archivists, documents activism and mutual aid in response to the COVID-19 pandemic, starting in 2020. The collection consists of archived websites on topics such as tenants rights, workers organizing surrounding unsafe working conditions, racism, and decarceration.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Google drive domains (drive.google.com) were partially captured but cannot be played back in Wayback. Instagram pages were captured using Webrecorder, but cannot be played back in Wayback.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Websites are selected by curators Shannon O'Neill and Michael Koncewicz and web archivist Nicole Greenhouse through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession numbers associated with these websites are 2020.040, 2021.002, 2021.003, 2021.005, 2021.007, 2021.012, 2021.016, 2021.047, 2021.051, 2021.067, 2021.084, 2022.006, 2022.023, 2022.032, 2022.033, 2022.034, 2022.035, 2022.054, 2022.069, 2022.074, 2022.089, 2023.006, 2023.028, 2023.034, 2023.58, 2023.069, 2023.099, and 2023.105.
Scope and Contents
The NYC COVID-19 Web Activism Collection documents activists' use of social media and the internet to create content, online campaigns, online actions, virtual mutual aid networks and funds to highlight, resist, and call attention to ways in which COVID-19 has impacted New York City physically, emotionally, politically, and economically. This collection also focused on the ways in which this activism names and addresses the ways in which COVID-19 has disproportionately affected low income communities of color in New York City. Subjects covered within the scope of this collection include organizing around tenants rights and rent strikes; housing insecurity; decarceration campaigns and efforts to raise bail for incarcerated individuals (especially those facing COVID-19 outbreaks in New York City jails); efforts to confront and combat anti-Asian racism; demilitarization campaigns; efforts to confront and combat environmental racism; organizing around access to healthcare; neighborhood autonomy and agency; and support and organizing for workers who are striking against unsafe work conditions, lack of hazard pay, and/or lack of benefits. This is an artificial collection, materials were selected by Tamiment curators and arranged by an archivist.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically by creator.
Conditions Governing Access
Majority of the collection is open to researchers without restrictions. Some materials are closed to protect the privacy of activists.
Historical Note
In March 2020, non-essential businesses throughout New York City closed in an effort to contain COVID-19, a respiratory virus that first identified in December 2019. The virus and the closures disproportionally affected systematically excluded groups. Within days of the shutdown, activists began to organize to provide mutual aid and information about the COVID-19 to support sex workers, veterans, immigrants, LGBTQIA people, incarcerated people, workers, and others. Over the course of the pandemic, these individuals and organizations pushed for worker protections, housing and tenant relief, decarceration, and called attention to ways in which COVID-19 has impacted New York City physically, emotionally, politically, and economically. During the pandemic, George Floyd, a black man, was killed by Derek Chauvin, a white police officer, in May 2020. This led to protests calling for the abolishment of the police and a resurgence in the Black Lives Matter movement. As the pandemic continued into 2021 and 2022, pushes for a "return to normal" by the establishment and government--despite continued resurgences in COVID-19 cases and deaths--led to activists pushing for rent assistance, an eviction moratorium, vaccine mandates, masking, ventilation and other environmental concerns, unionization efforts, city budget reforms, safe staffing for healthcare workers, and more permanent actions to keep people safe and healthy. As of this writing in April 2022, the pandemic is still an active part of life.
Appraisal
Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. The collection was rescoped to allow for Google documents, videos, and Airtable forms embedded in the website.
COVID-19 (Disease); Housing -- Law and legislation.; Undocumented Immigrants; Street vendors; Nurses -- Labor unions -- United States.; Sex workers; Harm reduction; Prison abolition movements; Truck drivers -- Labor unions -- United States.; Strikes and lockouts -- United States.; Household employees -- United States; Housing and health; Teachers' unions.; Bail
- Naming the Lost Memorials: the Many Losses from Covid-19, July 2023; #NamingTheLost (Box Electronic Records)
  Scope and Contents
  Naming The Lost Memorials (NTLM) and City Lore is at work on a public art COVID memorial which was on view at Green-wood Cemetery in Brooklyn from May 3-29, 2023. The theme of the memorial, created with help from twenty New York City community partners, is "The Many Losses from Covid-19." A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Discussion: Repair, Reparation, Refusal, July 2023; 1014 (Gallery) (Box Electronic Records)
  Video of Humanities for Humans event at 1014. Website features a description of the event, speaker biographies, and a reading list.
- Long COVID: A Brief Overview, July 2023; American Society on Aging (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Erica Spatz in Generations: American Society on Aging. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Learning from the Virus, July 2023; Artforum (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Paul B. Preciado in Artforum. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Asian American / Asian Research Institute, July 2023; Asian American/Asian Research Institute (Box Electronic Records)
  The Asian American / Asian Research Institute (AAARI) was established on November 19, 2001, by The City University of New York (CUNY) Board of Trustees, in a resolution introduced by Chancellor Matthew Goldstein. The Institute is a university-wide scholarly research and resource center that focuses on policies and issues that affect Asians and Asian Americans. It covers four areas: Asian American Studies; East Asian Studies; South Asian Studies; and Trade & Technology Studies. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Corona Conversations: A Year of Plague & Protests, July-August 2023; Asian American/Asian Research Institute (Box Electronic Records)
  CUNY FORUM 8:1 featured essays; analysis; literary, graphic, and poetic responses; conversations and community resources around the global COVID-19 pandemic and the linked Black Lives Matter protests from comparative Asian American and international Asian perspectives. Contributing writers hail from, or originate in the U.S., Peoples Republic of China, Taiwan, Myanmar, Philippines, India, Sri Lanka, Macao, the EU, and other places. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Mapping Covid-19's Transnational Implications for Women Workers, July-August 2023; Asian American/Asian Research Institute (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Lee Xie for the CUNY Forum 8. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- A World Remembers: Memorials honor COVID-19's 5 million dead, July 2023; The Associated Press (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Colleen Barry in the Associated Press. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- The COVID Tracking Project, July 2023; The Atlantic Monthly (Box Electronic Records)
  The COVID Tracking Project is a volunteer organization launched from The Atlantic and dedicated to collecting and publishing the data required to understand the COVID-19 outbreak in the United States. As of March 2021, they stopped collecting data. The website is divided into the following sections: federal COVID data, nursing homes and long-term care data, race and COVID, vaccination data, and analysis and updates. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- The Final Pandemic Betrayal, July 2023; The Atlantic Monthly (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Ed Yong in the Atlantic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- How Will the Future Remember COVID-19?, July 2023; The Atlantic Monthly (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Ian Bogost in the Atlantic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- The Pandemic's Legacy Is Already Clear, July 2023; The Atlantic Monthly (Box Electronic Records)
- The Audre Lorde Project, May 2020-February 2022; Audre Lorde Project (Box Electronic Records)
  The Audre Lorde Project (ALP) is a Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Two Spirit, Trans and Gender Nonconforming (LGBTSTGNC) People of Color center for community organizing in New York City. ALP works for progressive social and economic justice and the promotion of community wellness. The ALP "Know Your Housing Rights During COVID-19" guide was written by Kerbie Joseph, ALP's Safe Outside the System Coordinator. It provides tenants rights information around eviction, rent demands from landlords, utility shut-offs, and shares strategies for collective tenant organizing.
- Hey Neighbor NYC, July 2023; Bari, Kisha; Chang, Jasmin (Box Electronic Records)
  Hey Neighbor NYC connects differing cultural communities across the five boroughs through storytelling and public art. The website contains biographies of the artists. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Hey Neighbor NYC Instagram, July-August 2023; Bari, Kisha; Chang, Jasmin (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Resources for Undocumented Immigrants, June 2020-February 2022; Betancourt Macias Family Scholarship Foundation (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page listing financial, medical, mutual aid, food, and legal resources for undocumented immigrants organized by state.
- Beyond Prisons Prisoner Support Guide the Coronavirus Crisis, May-June 2020; Beyond Prisons (Box Electronic Records)
  Document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page describing best practices on supporting incarcerated people during the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Covid Maps Reveal Personal Pandemic Landscapes, July 2023; Bloomberg News (Firm) (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Laura Bliss and Jessica Martin in Bloomberg. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- #SENIORLIVESMATTER: Bronx Senior Photo League, July 2023; Bronx Documentary Center (Box Electronic Records)
  Virtual exhibit by the Bronx Senior Photo League presented by the Bronx Documentary Center. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Homegoing, July 2023; Brown University. Department of Africana Studies (Box Electronic Records)
  Memorial of Black Americans killed by COVID-19. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Sex Work and COVID-19: Guidelines for Sex Workers, Clients, Third Parties, and Allies, June 2020-February 2022; Butterfly: Asian and Migrant Sex Workers Support Network; Maggie's Toronto Sex Workers Action Project (Box Electronic Records)
  Document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page describing protective guidelines for sex workers, clients, third parties, and allies.
- COVID-19 Public Art Projects, July 2023; California (Box Electronic Records)
  18 public artworks developed in partnership with the Center at Sierra Health Foundation and the California COVID-19 Public Arts Project designed to raise awareness of actions Californians have taken to help stop the spread of COVID-19. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- CSU Chico Humanities Center: Visiting Scholar Diana Taylor, "Reparative Memory", July 2023; California State University (Box Electronic Records)
  YouTube video of a talk given as part of the Visiting Scholar Lecture Series, 2021-2022, at the California State University Chico Humanities Center. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- COVID-19 Documentaries: The Politics of Representation and Production, July 2023; Cineaste (Box Electronic Records)
  Essay by Bao Feng and Charles Musser in Cineaste. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Long COVID Symptoms Most Common Among Latinos and Residents of The Bronx, July 2023; THE CITY (Box Electronic Records)
  Article in THE CITY by Sarah Luft. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- MISSING THEM: Remembering the New Yorkers We've Lost to‌ COVID‑19 Archived Website, July 2023; THE CITY (Box Electronic Records)
  Memorial project of THE CITY, Columbia Journalism School, Brown Institute for Media Innovation and the Craig Newmark Graduate School of Journalism at CUNY documenting New Yorkers who died to COVID-19. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Confronting COVID-19 Loss in Harlem, July 2023; Columbia University (Box Electronic Records)
  A Columbia World Projects project aimed to reduce COVID-19 related grief in Harlem's Black community by partnering Columbia researchers with local faith leaders and other community leaders to address intense and pervasive grief that has emerged as a result of the pandemic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- How Do You Memorialize Loss, Violence, and Injustice?, July 2023; Columbia University (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Angeline Joelle Dimambro in Columbia News. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- NYC Covid-19 Oral History, Narrative and Memory Archive, July 2023; Columbia University (Box Electronic Records)
  Oral history project at Columbia University's INCITE and the Oral History Archives at Columbia building an archive documenting New York City's experience of the pandemic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- The Zip Code Memory Project Provides Connection, Healing, and Plans for Change, July 2023; Columbia University (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Maggie Barrows in Columbia Neighbors. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- What World Is This?: A Pandemic Phenomenology, July 2023; Columbia University. Press (Box Electronic Records)
  Catalog entry for What World Is This?: A Pandemic Phenomenology by Judith Butler. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Corona Courier, June 2020-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  Corona Courier is a mutual-aid group of NYC cyclists who provide free no-contact delivery service to most at-risk community members during the COVID-19 public health crisis. They have around 450 volunteers located across Manhattan, Brooklyn, Queens and The Bronx. Along with general courier work, they help with grocery shopping and food assistance in Brooklyn, Manhattan and Queens. In The Bronx they are currently partnering with Montefiore Hospital and BXMpowerment Project to help with their pantry deliveries.
- Undocumented Worker Fund, May 2020-February 2022; Cosecha (Box Electronic Records)
  Cosecha is "a nonviolent movement fighting for permanent protection, dignity, and respect for the 11 million undocumented immigrants in the United States." In response to the COVID-19 crisis, Cosecha established an undocumented workers fund campaign, encouraging individuals to donate their federal government stimulus checks to support undocumented workers who were excluded from participation in the stimulus check program.
- How Movimiento Cosecha operates a COVID-19 fund by and for undocumented immigrants, February 2022; Cosecha (Box Electronic Records)
  Blog post from Cosecha detailing how funds were used from the undocumented workers fund.
- Nos Cuida La Comunidad: Cosecha's COVID-19 Fund for Undocumented Workers has Redistributed $1 Million, February 2022; Cosecha (Box Electronic Records)
- Bail Payer Volunteer Sign-Up, June 2020-ongoing; COVID Bail Out NYC (Box Electronic Records)
  Google form for bail payer volunteer sign-up.
- COVID Bail Out NYC Attorney/Social Worker Requests, January 2022-ongoing; COVID Bail Out NYC (Box Electronic Records)
  Google form for attorney and/or social worker requests.
- COVID Bail Out NYC Community Requests, August 2020-ongoing; COVID Bail Out NYC (Box Electronic Records)
  Google form for requests for bail out.
- COVID Bail Out NYC, May 2020-September 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
  COVID Bail Out NYC is a volunteer, emergency grassroots initiative partnering with Emergency Release Fund and Black Alliance for Just Immigration to support bailing incarcerated people from Rikers Island Prison and in New York City jails. COVID Bail-Out NYC centralizes funding to post bail, provide support to public defenders, and providing post-release support. Through the website, individuals can donate funding and volunteer to post bail. It also calls for trained social workers, mediators, healers, and individuals trained in conflict resolution to volunteer time to support individuals upon their release from prison or jail. The website also allows for attorneys to make referrals for incarcerated individuals who need to post bail. The website also includes a semi-regularly updated Instagram feed for @covidbailoutnyc which includes update posts on the number of individual who have been released from prison or jail due to the initiative.
- Peoples Bail Out NYC, March 2023-ongoing; COVID Bail Out NYC (Box Electronic Records)
  Peoples Bail Out NYC, formerly COVID Bail Out NYC, centralizes funding to post bail, provide support to public defenders, and providing post-release support. Through the website, individuals can donate funding and volunteer to post bail. It also calls for trained social workers, mediators, healers, and individuals trained in conflict resolution to volunteer time to support individuals upon their release from prison or jail. The website also allows for attorneys to make referrals for incarcerated individuals who need to post bail as well as family and friends to request a bail out.
- Peoples Bail Out NYC Twitter, May 2023-ongoing; COVID Bail Out NYC (Box Electronic Records)